Jean Burden Papers
Jean Burden Papers
1931-1992
Burden, Jean.
11 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, author, poetry editor for Yankee magazine. Born 1914. Correspondence, manuscript and published articles, poems, and memoirs; and memorabilia, including photographs.
148876
Biographical History
Jean Burden (1914- ) is an American poet, essayist, anthologist, teacher and editor. Born in Waukegan, Illinois, she attended the University of Chicago, graduating in 1936. She has been West Coast editor of Faith Today and of Yankee magazine, where she later (1955) took a position as poetry editor. She has published books of poetry and of essays, and her work has appeared in numerous national magazines including Poetry, Atlantic, American Scholar, Trace, Saturday Review, Virginia Quarterly Review, Better Homes and Gardens, Mademoiselle, Prairie Schooner, Southern Review. She has also published several books on pet care,
In addition to her writing, for nearly ten years (1956-1965) Ms Burden served as administrative officer for the Meals for Millions Foundation in Los Angeles, California. She has taught both privately and in workshops, and since 1966 has done freelance public relations work.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Jean Burden Papers consists entirely of Correspondence-subject files. Correspondents include artists, authors, editors, and publishers, as well as friends and family. Notable correspondents include Russell Banks, Eric Barker, Robert Bly, Arna Bontemps, William Stanley Braithwaite, Gwendolyn Brooks, John Ciardi, Norman Cousins, Peter De Vries, August Derleth, Ivan Doig, Helene Hanff, Archibald Macleish, Rollo May, Christopher Morley, Alfred Neumann, May Sarton, Charles M. Schulz, John Tagliabue, Laurens Van der Post, Alan Watts, Thornton Wilder, and many more.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence-subject files are arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Women Authors; Abbe, George, 1911-1989.; Adler, Carol (Poet); Akers, Dana Kneeland.; Allen, Sara Van Alstyne.; Ames, Amyas.; Ames, Evelyn, 1908-1990.; Armour, Anobel, 1908-; Aronin, Ben, 1904-; Athill, Diana.; Baker, Phyllis.; Banks, Russell, 1940-; Barker, Eric, 1905-1973.; Barker, Lucy Munro.; Baskett, Lois R.; Blackwell, Betsy Talbot.; Block, Allan, 1923-2013.; Bly, Robert.; Boggs, W. Arthur.; Bond, Harold, 1939-; Bontemps, Arna, 1902-1973.; Borgatta, Isabel Case.; Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1878-1962.; Brasier, Virginia.; Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1917-2000.; Broomell, Myron Henry, 1906-; Bullock, Marie, 1911-1986.; Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971.; Burden, Jean.; Carpenter, Margaret.; Carruth, Hayden, 1921-2008.; Chambers, John, -1801.; Cherwinski, Joseph, 1915-; Ciardi, John, 1916-1986.; Ciletti, Jim.; Claytor, Gertrude.; Cole, Lucretia.; Congdon, Kirby.; Cousins, Norman.; Coze, Paul.; Dayton, Irene, 1922-; Derleth, August, 1909-1971.; Deutsch, Babette, 1895-1982.; De Vries, Peter, 1910-1993.; Dickey, James.; Dillon, George, 1906-1968.; Dooley, Thomas A. (Thomas Anthony), 1927-1961.; Eberhart, Richard, 1904-2005.; Exman, Eugene.; Farber, Norma.; Fitzell, Lincoln, 1903-1958.; Flanner, Hildegarde, 1899-1987.; Flanner, Janet, 1892-1978.; Frank, Nancy (Nancy K.), 1954-; Frumkin, Gene.; Funk, Peter, 1921-; Garrett, Eileen J. (Eileen Jeanette), 1893-1970.; Gould, Jean, 1909-1993.; Gullans, Charles B.; Haag, John.; Hale, Judson D.; Hall, Donald, 1928-; Hallinan, Nancy.; Harlow, Michael.; Honig, Edwin.; Howard, Frances Minturn.; Inez, Colette.; Jacobsen, Josephine.; Jerome, Judson.; Joost, Nicholas.; Junkins, Donald, 1931-; Kaufman, Mervyn D.; Kahn, Hannah.; Keith, Joseph Joel.; Kellogg, Hansen.; Kornitzer, Bela.; Kretz, Thomas S.; Kunitz, Stanley, 1905-2006.; Liebler, H. B.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Masters, Marcia Lee.; Mathewson, William.; May, Rollo.; Mayerson, Charlotte, 1927-; Miles, Josephine, 1911-1985.; Miller, Sigmund Stephen.; Miranda, Gary.; Moore, Merrill, 1903-1957.; Morehouse, Kathleen.; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957.; Nemerov, Howard.; Neumann, Alfred, 1895-1952.; Nims, John Frederick, 1913-1999.; Noyes, Sandy.; Oakes, Maud, 1903-1990.; O'Hehir, Diana, 1929-; Oliver, Mary, 1935-; Owings, Margaret.; Pedrick, Jean, 1922-; Pitter, Ruth, 1897-1992.; Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-2001.; Rago, Henry, 1915-1969.; Rajagopal, D.; Raymond, Richard C.; Richardson, Dorothy Lee.; Riggs, Dionis Coffin.; Robbins, Martin.; Roddan, Brooks.; Rollins, Leighton, 1900-; Rose, Karen.; Roseliep, Raymond, 1917-1983.; Ross, Nancy Wilson, 1901-1986.; Sagendorph, Robb Hansell.; Sarton, May, 1912-1995.; Schevill, James Erwin, 1920-2009.; Schulz, Charles M. (Charles Monroe), 1922-2000.; Scott, Winfield Townley, 1910-1968.; Shapiro, Karl, 1913-2000.; Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012.; Smith, Hallett, 1907-1996.; Snow, Wilbert, 1884-1977.; Stafford, William, 1914-1993.; Stoloff, Carolyn.; Swenson, Karen.; Swenson, May.; Tagliabue, John, 1923-; Triem, Eve, 1902-1992.; Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1886-1970.; Van der Post, Laurens.; Watts, Alan, 1915-1973.; West, Cristy.; Wheelock, John Hall, 1886-1978.; White, Betty, 1924-; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975.; Worthington, Thomas.; Wright, Celeste Turner.; Zimmer, Paul.; Meals for Millions, Inc.; Yankee (Dublin, N.H.); American poetry -- 20th century.; American poetry -- Women authors.; Authors, American.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Pet food industry -- Public relations.; Women authors, American.; Women poets, American.; Autobiographies (literary works); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Authors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jean Burden, 1969-2002.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Burden, David and Virginia (Box 1)
  - Burden family (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
  - Prussing, Rudy E. (Box 1)
  - Prussing family (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
  - A, miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Aal, Katharyn Machan (Box 1)
  - Abbe, George Bancroft (Box 1)
  - Academy of American Poets (Box 1)
    See also Bullock, Marie
  - Ackerson, Duane (Box 1)
  - Adler, Carol (Box 1)
  - Akers, Dana Kneeland (Box 1)
  - Aldridge, Richard (Box 1)
  - Allen, Sara Van Alstyne (Box 1)
  - American Academy in Rome (Box 1)
  - The American Home (Box 1)
  - The American Scholar (Box 1)
  - Ames, Amyas (Box 1)
  - Ames, Bernice (Box 1)
  - Ames, Eli (Box 1)
  - Ames, Evelyn, 1955-1984; undated; 14 folders (Box 1)
  - Ames, Joan (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Doug (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Tom (Box 1)
  - Angus, Sylvia (Box 1)
  - Appel, Dori (Box 1)
  - Armour, Anobel (Box 1)
  - Aronin, Ben (Box 1)
  - Athill, Diana (Box 1)
  - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 1)
    See also Weeks, Edward
  - Auf der Heide, Lisl (Box 1)
  - Author & Journalist (Box 1)
  - Axeen, Lyssa (Box 1)
  - B, miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Baker, John (Box 1)
  - Baker, Phyllis (Box 1)
  - Banks, Russell (Box 1)
  - Barker, Eric, 1953-1959 (Box 1)
  - Barker, Eric, 1960-1971; undated (Box 2)
  - Barker, Lucy Munro (Box 2)
  - Barnes, Kate (Box 2)
  - Barnes, Margaret W. (Box 2)
  - Barrett, Susan E. (Box 2)
  - Baskett, Lois R. (Box 2)
  - Behm, Richard (Box 2)
  - Bentley, Beth (Box 2)
  - Berryman, Jo (Box 2)
  - Blackwell, Betsy Talbot (Box 2)
  - Block, Allen (Box 2)
  - Bly, Robert (Box 2)
  - Boggs, W. Arthur (Box 2)
  - Bond, Bruce (Box 2)
  - Bond, Harold (Box 2)
  - Bontemps, Arna Wendell (Box 2)
  - Booker, Stephen Todd (Box 2)
  - Borestone Mountain Poetry Awards (Box 2)
    See also Poetry Awards
  - Borgatta, Isabel Case (Box 2)
  - Borgatta, Robert (Box 2)
  - Bowers, Neal (Box 2)
  - Boyers, Robert (Box 2)
    See also Salmagundi
  - Braiser, Virginia (Box 2)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley (Box 2)
  - Bray, Louise (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn (Box 2)
  - Broomell, Myron, 1949-1971 (Box 2)
  - Broughton, T. Alan (Box 2)
  - Brown, Lea W. ("Topaz") (Box 2)
  - Brown, Richard (Box 2)
  - Bullock, Marie and Hugh (Box 2)
  - Bunche, Ralph (Box 2)
  - Burgess, Stella Fisher (Box 2)
  - Burns, Ralph (Box 2)
  - Burns, William (Box 2)
  - Butcher, Grace (Box 2)
  - C, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Caldwell, Katherine (Box 2)
  - Cameron, Eleanor (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Joan (Box 2)
  - Caples, Robert Cole (Box 2)
  - Carlisle, Thomas John (Box 2)
  - Carnation Company (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York (Box 2)
  - Carpenter, Margaret (Box 2)
  - Carpenter, Nan C. (Box 3)
  - Carruth, Hayden (Box 3)
  - Carter, John Stewart (Box 3)
  - Casto, Robert Clayton (Box 3)
  - Chambers, John (Box 3)
  - Chase, Naomi Feigelson (Box 3)
  - Cherwinski, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Chitwood, Michael (Box 3)
  - Ciardi, John (Box 3)
  - Ciletti, Jim (Box 3)
  - Clare, William (Box 3)
  - Clarke & Way, Inc., See October House
  - Claytor, Gertrude (Box 3)
  - Clewell, David (Box 3)
  - Coastlines Literary Magazine (Box 3)
  - Cole, Henri (Box 3)
  - Cole, Lucretia (Box 3)
  - Cole, Madelene (Box 3)
  - Cole, Mary (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Jane (Box 3)
  - Colorado Quarterly (Box 3)
  - Congdon, Kirby (Box 3)
  - Coulter, Frances (Box 3)
  - Courtois, Flora (Box 3)
  - Cousins, Norman (Box 3)
  - Coze, Paul (Box 3)
  - Cramer, Barbara (Box 3)
  - Crawford, John W. (Box 3)
  - The Critic (Box 3)
  - Crooker, Barbara (Box 3)
  - D, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Dacey, Philip (Box 3)
  - Dalton, Dorothy (Box 3)
  - Daniel, John (Box 3)
  - Darling, Charles (Box 3)
  - Dauer, Rosamond (Box 3)
  - D'Auria, Gemma (Box 3)
  - Dayton, Irene (Box 3)
  - De Frees, Madeline (Box 3)
  - Dempsey, Ivy and Joe (Box 3)
  - DePaur, Leonard (Box 3)
  - DePoy, Phillip (Box 3)
  - Der Hovanessian, Diana (Box 3)
  - Derleth, August William (Box 3)
  - Desy, Peter (Box 3)
  - Deutsche, Babette (Box 3)
  - DeVries, Peter and Katinka (Box 3)
  - Dickey, James (Box 3)
  - Dillon, George (Box 3)
  - Dine, Carol (Box 3)
  - Djanikian, Gregory (Box 3)
  - Dobbins, Mardell Dressler (Box 3)
  - Doherty, Edward Joseph (Box 3)
  - Doig, Ivan (Box 3)
  - Donahey, William and Mary (Box 3)
  - Donnelly, Susan (Box 3)
  - Dooley, Thomas (Box 3)
  - Dorman, Sonya (Box 3)
  - Downes, Edith S. (Box 3)
  - Downey, Bill (Box 3)
  - Drake, Leah Bodine (Box 3)
  - Dubroff, Susanne (Box 3)
  - Duryee, Mary Ballard (Box 3)
  - E, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Eaton, Charles Edward (Box 3)
  - Eberhart, Richard (Box 3)
  - Ellis, Betty (Box 3)
  - Ericksen, Jane and Stanford C. (Box 3)
  - [Paul S.] Eriksson, Publisher (Box 3)
  - Exman, Eugene (Box 3)
  - F, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Farber, Norma (Box 3)
  - Feldman, Ruth (Box 3)
  - Fellowship Church (Box 3)
  - Fincke, Gary (Box 3)
  - Fischer, John (Box 3)
  - Fitzell, Lincoln (Box 3)
  - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1961-1981; 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1982-1988; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Flanner, Janet (Box 4)
  - Fles, Barthold (Box 4)
  - Fogel, Alice B. (Box 4)
  - Folds, Suzanne Lord (Box 4)
  - Ford, Edsel (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 4)
  - Fowler, Jay Bradford (Box 4)
  - Fox, Cecilia (Box 4)
  - Frank, Jacqueline (Box 4)
  - Frank, Nancy (Box 4)
  - Freedman, Louis N. (Box 4)
  - Fromm, Erich (Box 4)
  - Frumkin, Gene (Box 4)
  - Funk, Peter (Box 4)
  - Furlaud, Alice (Box 4)
  - G, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Gallagher, Tess (Box 4)
  - Galvin, Brendan (Box 4)
  - Gardner, Isabella (Box 4)
  - Garrett, Eileen (Box 4)
  - The Georgia Review (Box 4)
  - Gerber, Merrill Joan (Box 4)
  - Gibb, Robert (Box 4)
  - Glaser, Elton (Box 4)
  - Goldman, Judy (Box 4)
  - Golffing, Barbara Gibbs (Box 4)
  - Gottlieb, Lois D. (Box 4)
  - Gould, Jean (Box 4)
  - Green, Jane Nugent (Box 4)
  - Gribbin, George (Box 4)
  - Grossman, Allen (Box 4)
  - [John Simon] Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 4)
  - Guideposts (Box 4)
  - Gullans, Charles (Box 4)
  - Gustafson, Joseph (Box 4)
  - H, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Haag, John (Box 4)
  - Hale, Judson, See Yankee
  - Hall, Amanda Benjamin (Box 4)
  - Hall, Donald (Box 4)
  - Hallinan, Nancy (Box 4)
  - Handy, Nixeon Civille (Box 4)
  - Hanff, Helene (Box 4)
  - Hansen, Tom (Box 4)
  - Harleman, Ann (Box 4)
  - Harlow, Michael (Box 4)
  - Harper & Brothers (Box 4)
  - Harris, Claudia (Box 4)
  - Harris, Norene (Box 4)
  - Harrison, Janet E. (Box 4)
  - Harter, Penny (Box 4)
  - Hashmey, Nuri (Box 4)
  - Hay, Sara Henderson (Box 4)
  - Hearst, James (Box 4)
  - Hellyer, Connie Hopkins (Box 4)
  - Helfferich, Reginald (Box 4)
  - Heuser, Gunnar (Box 4)
  - Hillyer, Laurie (Box 4)
  - Hodgen, John (Box 4)
  - Holden, Raymond P. and Barbara (Box 4)
  - Holmes, John (Box 4)
  - Holt Magazines (Box 4)
  - Hongo, Garrett Kaoru (Box 4)
  - Honig, Edwin (Box 4)
  - Hooper, Patricia (Box 4)
  - House Beautiful (Box 4)
  - Howard, Frances Minturn, 1953-1956; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Howard, Frances Minturn, 1957-1990; undated; 13 folders (Box 5)
  - Humes, Harry (Box 5)
  - Hyett, Barbara Helfgott (Box 5)
  - I, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Ito, Miyoko (Box 5)
  - Inez, Colette (Box 5)
  - J, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Jacobsen, Josephine (Box 5)
  - Jacobsen, Marge (Box 5)
  - Jacoby, Grover (Box 5)
  - James, Gwen (Box 5)
  - Janzen, Jean (Box 5)
  - Jean Burden Poetry Series (California State University, Los Angeles) (Box 5)
  - Jensen, Jeff (Box 5)
  - Jennings, Leslie (Box 5)
  - Jerome, Judson (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Dave and Jane (Box 5)
  - Joost, Nicholas (Box 5)
  - Junkins, Donald (Box 5)
  - K, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Kahn, Hannah (Box 5)
  - Karr, Mary (Box 5)
  - Kaufman, Mervyn D. (Box 5)
  - Keating, Diane (Box 5)
  - Kefferstan, Jean, See Pedrick, Jean
  - Keith, Joseph Joel (Box 5)
  - Keithley, George (Box 5)
  - Kellogg, Hanson (Box 5)
  - King, Nancy (Box 5)
  - Kinkead, Garreth P. (Box 5)
  - Kirk, Lee Crawley (Box 5)
  - Kirkup, James (Box 5)
  - Kirschner, Elizabeth (Box 5)
  - Kizer, Carolyn (Box 5)
  - Kohlsaat, Caroline (Box 5)
  - Kopp, Karl (Box 6)
  - Kornitzer, Bela (Box 6)
  - Kretz, Thomas (Box 6)
  - Krishnamurti Writings, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Kroll, Ernest (Box 6)
  - Kumin, Maxine (Box 6)
  - Kunitz, Stanley (Box 6)
  - L, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - La Belle, Jenijoy (Box 6)
  - La Bombard, Joan (Box 6)
  - La Cossitt, Henry (Box 6)
  - Laing, Alexander (Box 6)
  - Laird, Ken (Box 6)
  - Lamb, Elizabeth S. (Box 6)
  - Lane, Frona (Box 6)
  - Langland, Joseph (Box 6)
  - Lazard, Naomi (Box 6)
  - Lesemann, Maurice (Box 6)
  - Levenberg, Diane (Box 6)
  - Levy, Robert J. (Box 6)
  - Libbey, Elizabeth (Box 6)
  - Lieberman, Laurence (Box 6)
  - Liebler, W. B. (Box 6)
  - Lineaweaver, Marion McLennan (Box 6)
  - Little, Geraldine Clinton (Box 6)
  - Loeser, Katinka, See DeVries, Peter and Katinka
  - Logan, John (Box 6)
  - Logue, Carol Jean (Box 6)
  - Lohmann, Jeanne (Box 6)
  - Longchamps, Joanne de (Box 6)
  - Lowe, Naoma and Mac (Box 6)
  - Lunn, Jean (Box 6)
  - M, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - McDonald, Walter (Box 6)
  - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 6)
  - MacLeish, Roderick (Box 6)
  - McMillan, Jackie (Box 6)
  - MacMillan, William J. (Box 6)
  - McNair, Wesley (Box 6)
  - McQuilkin, Eleanor A. (Box 6)
  - McQuilkin, Rennie (Box 6)
  - Mademoiselle, See Blackwell, Betsy Talbot
  - Magee, Irene (Box 6)
  - Majerova, Vlasta (Box 6)
  - Mandel, Peter (Box 6)
  - Manfred, Freya F. (Box 6)
  - Marcus, Mordecai (Box 6)
  - Masinga, Edward (Box 6)
  - Masters, Marcia Lee (Box 6)
  - Masterson, Dan (Box 6)
  - Mathewson, William (Box 6)
  - May, Rollo (Box 6)
  - Mayerson, Charlotte, See Random House, Inc.
  - Meinke, Peter (Box 6)
  - Menebroker, Ann (Box 6)
  - Merriam, Eve (Box 6)
  - Merrifield, Charles W. (Box 6)
  - Middlebrook, Diane (Box 6)
  - Miles, Josephine (Box 6)
  - Miller, Henry (Box 6)
  - Miller, Sigmund and Phyllis (Box 6)
  - Millett, Ricardo (Box 6)
  - Mills, Laurel (Box 6)
  - Mirakentz, Claire (Box 6)
  - Miranda, Gary (Box 6)
  - Moore, Donald A., See Carnation Company
  - Moore, Merrill (Box 6)
  - Moose, Ruth (Box 6)
  - Morehouse, Kathleen Moore (Box 6)
  - Morgan, Margaret (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher (Box 6)
  - Morris, Alice (Box 6)
  - Mott, Michael (Box 6)
  - Munger, Hortense, See Roberts, Hortense Roberta
  - John Murray (Box 6)
  - N, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Nash, Mildred J. (Box 6)
  - Nash, Valery (Box 6)
  - Nathan, Ruth Notkins (Box 6)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 6)
  - Nelson, W. Dale (Box 6)
  - Nemerov, Howard (Box 6)
  - Nerber, John (Box 6)
  - Neumann, Alfred and Kitty (Box 6)
  - New England Review (Box 6)
  - The New Yorker (Box 6)
  - Nicholl, Louise Townsend (Box 6)
  - Nichols, Douglas (Box 6)
  - Nichols, Jeanne (Box 6)
  - Nims, John Frederick (Box 6)
  - Norris, William Clarkson (Box 7)
  - Noyes, Libby (Box 7)
  - Noyes, Charlotte (Box 7)
  - Noyes, Sandy (Box 7)
  - Nyhart, Nina (Box 7)
  - O, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Oakes, Maud (Box 7)
  - [Harold] Ober Associates Inc. (Box 7)
  - O'Conor, Norreys Jephson (Box 7)
  - October House, Inc. (Box 7)
  - Odam, Joyce (Box 7)
  - O'Hehir, Diana (Box 7)
  - Older, Julia (Box 7)
  - Oliver, Mary (Box 7)
  - [Harold] Orenstein, P.C. (Box 7)
  - Osborne, Mary Elizabeth (Box 7)
  - Owen, John S. (Box 7)
  - Owings, Margaret (Box 7)
  - Owings, Nathaniel A. (Box 7)
  - P, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Paquin, Olive Weaver (Box 7)
  - Parker, Bonnie Elizabeth (Box 7)
  - Parsons, Kitty (Box 7)
  - Pastan, Linda (Box 7)
  - Payne, Grace Visher (Box 7)
  - Pedrick, Jean (Box 7)
  - Peters, Robert (Box 7)
  - Pfingston, Roger (Box 7)
  - Pitter, Ruth (Box 7)
  - Poet & Critic, See Bowers, Neal
  - Poetry (Box 7)
  - Poetry Awards (Box 7)
    See also Borestone Mountain Poetry Awards
  - Poetry Society of Arnerica (Box 7)
  - Pond, Melora Hobbs (Box 7)
  - Popular Library (Box 7)
  - Powell, Dannye Romine (Box 7)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark (Box 7)
  - Prairie Schooner (Box 7)
  - Q, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Quagliano, Tony (Box 7)
  - R, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Radford, Miriam (Box 7)
  - Rago, Henry (Box 7)
  - Rajagopal, D. (Box 7)
  - Random House, Inc. (Box 7)
  - Ray, David (Box 7)
  - Raymond, Richard C. (Box 7)
  - Redbook Magazine (Box 7)
  - Redmayne, Helen (Box 7)
  - Reeves, Winnie (Box 7)
  - Reiter, Thomas (Box 7)
  - Replansky, Naomi (Box 7)
  - Rhoads, Geraldine (Box 7)
    See also Woman's Day
  - Richardson, Dorothy Lee (Box 7)
  - Ridl, John (Box 7)
  - Ridland, John (Box 7)
  - Riggs, Dionis Coffin (Box 7)
  - Robbins, Martin (Box 7)
  - Roberts, Hortense Roberta (Box 7)
  - Roddan, Brooks (Box 7)
  - Rogers, Bertha (Box 7)
  - Rollins, Leighton and Catherine (Box 7)
  - Rose, Florence (Box 7)
  - Rose, Karen (Box 7)
  - Roseliep, Raymond, 1957-1975; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Roseliep, Raymond, 1976-1983; undated; 11 folders (Box 8)
  - Rosen, Deborah Nodler (Box 8)
  - Rosenberg, Liz (Box 8)
  - Rosenthal, Irving (Box 8)
  - Rosenthal, M. L. (Box 8)
  - Ross, Nancy Wilson (Box 8)
  - Roycemore School (Box 8)
  - Rubin, Larry (Box 8)
  - Rubin, Maude (Box 8)
  - Ryf, Robert (Box 8)
  - S, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Sagendorph, Robb (Box 8)
  - Salmagundi (Box 8)
  - Salomon, Isidore Lawrence (Box 8)
  - Sarton, May (Box 8)
  - Sasso, Laurence J. (Box 8)
  - The Saturday Review (Box 8)
    See also Cousins, Norman
  - Scheibe, Jane (Box 8)
  - Schevill, James (Box 8)
  - Schmid, Marcia, See Masters, Marcia Lee
  - Schulz, Charles M. (Box 8)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley (Box 8)
  - [Charles] Scribner's Sons (Box 8)
  - Scroggs, Schiller (Box 8)
  - Serchuk, Peter (Box 8)
  - Sethness, Olin (Box 8)
  - Shapiro, Karl Jay (Box 8)
  - Shenandoah (Box 8)
  - Sherry, Pearl Andelson (Box 8)
  - Shoben, Edward Joseph (Box 8)
  - Simmons, John E. (Box 8)
  - Simpson, Louis (Box 8)
  - Skloot, Floyd (Box 8)
  - Slaughter, William Robert (Box 8)
  - Smith, Dave (Box 8)
  - Smith, Hallett Darius (Box 8)
  - Smith, Virginia (Box 8)
  - Smith, William Jay (Box 8)
  - Snow, Wilbert (Box 8)
  - Somers, Ann (Box 8)
  - Soniat, Katherine (Box 8)
  - Sorrells, Helen (Box 8)
  - The Southem Review (Box 8)
  - Southwest Review (Box 8)
  - Spacks, Barry (Box 8)
  - Spaulding, John (Box 8)
  - Spear, Sarah (Box 8)
  - Spence, Michael (Box 8)
  - Spires, Elizabeth (Box 8)
  - Stafford, William (Box 9)
  - Sternlieb, Barry (Box 9)
  - Stirling, Betty (Box 9)
  - Stirling family (Box 9)
  - Stift, Peter (Box 9)
  - Stoloff, Carolyn (Box 9)
  - Strand, Mark (Box 9)
  - Sugrue, Thomas (Box 9)
  - Sultan, Altoon (Box 9)
  - Sutton, Lee (Box 9)
  - Swain, Raymond C. (Box 9)
  - Sweeney, Barbara (Box 9)
  - Swenson, Karen (Box 9)
  - Swenson, May (Box 9)
  - Swist, Wally (Box 9)
  - T, miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Tagliabue, John (Box 9)
  - Tatch, Max (Box 9)
  - Taylor, Sarah Wingate (Box 9)
  - Thomas, Warren (Box 9)
  - Thompson, Shannon (Box 9)
  - Thurman, Howard (Box 9)
  - Triem, Eve (Box 9)
  - U, miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - University of Central Florida (Box 9)
  - University Presses of Florida (Box 9)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr (Box 9)
  - Urbain, John (Box 9)
  - Urdang, Constance (Box 9)
  - V, miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Van der Post, Laurens (Box 9)
  - Van Duyn, Mona (Box 9)
  - Viereck, Peter (Box 9)
  - Vinal, Harold (Box 9)
  - Vinuya, Amado A. (Box 9)
  - Voelker, Elizabeth (Box 9)
  - W, miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Wallace, Ronald (Box 9)
  - Washburn, Owen Ridington (Box 9)
  - Waters, Mary Ann (Box 9)
  - Watts, Alan (Box 9)
  - Way, David (Box 9)
    See also October House, Inc.
  - Wayne, Jane O. (Box 9)
  - Weeks, Edward (Box 9)
  - Weismiller, Edward Ronald (Box 9)
  - Wesleyan University Press (Box 9)
  - West, Christy (Box 10)
  - Westburg, Phyllis, See [Harold] Ober Associates Inc.
  - Westerfield, Nancy G. (Box 10)
  - Wheatcroft, John (Box 10)
  - Wheelock, John Hall (Box 10)
  - Wheelwright, Philip (Box 10)
  - White, Betty (Box 10)
  - White, Joan (Box 10)
  - Whitney, Ross (Box 10)
  - Widdemer, Margaret (Box 10)
  - Wicks, Susan (Box 10)
  - Wieck, Fred (Box 10)
  - Wilbur, Richard (Box 10)
  - Wilder, Thornton (Box 10)
  - Wllard, Ruth (Box 10)
  - Williams, Miller (Box 10)
  - Wimmer, Jerry (Box 10)
  - Witt, Harold (Box 10)
  - Woman's Day (Box 10)
  - Wood, Renate (Box 10)
  - Woods, Christopher (Box 10)
  - Woodcock, Joan, See Ames, Joan
  - Worthington, Thomas (Box 10)
  - Wright, Celeste (Box 10)
  - Wrigley, Robert (Box 10)
  - Y, miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Yankee, Inc. (Box 10)
  - Yellott, Barbara (Box 10)
  - Yost, Charles and Felicity (Box 10)
  - Young, Nancy, See Ross, Nancy Wilson
  - Z, miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Zadravec, Katharine (Box 10)
  - Zeigler, Lila (Box 10)
  - Zimmer, Paul (Box 10)
  - Zimmer, Peg (Box 10)
  - Unidentified (Box 10)